I see life in angles
in lines of perspective – the slow turn of a head
the blink of an eye
subtle glimpses of magic
other folk might pass by
Cameras help me translate, interpret and understand what I see
It’s a simple act that keeps me grinnin
I never set out to become anything in particular
only to live creatively
and push the scope of my experience for adventure
and for passion
They still all mean something to me
same as most anyone with dreams
My heart bleeds celtic blood
and I magnetize the familiar frontiers
The raw brutal cold coastlands for the right waveriders to challenge
this is where my heart beats hardest
I try to pay tribute to that magic through photographs
Weathering the endless staunch for rare glimpses of magic each winter
is both a blessing
and a curse I relish
I wanna see waveriding documented the way I see it in my head
and the way I feel it in the sea
This is a strange set of skills to begin to acquire
and is only achievable through time spent riding waves
All sorts of waves on all sorts of crafts
This is more time learning out on the water
floating in the sea amongst lumps and swells
you always learn something
It’s been a lifelong wise old classroom teacher of sorts
and hopefully
it always will be
Buried beneath headlands
shaping the coast
mind-blowing images of empty waves burn away at me
Solid ocean swells powering through deep cold water
heavy waves weighs we'll wait
they coaxed from comfortable routine
ignite the imagination
conveys some of the viny spark
whisper possibilities
conjure the situations I thrive amongst and love to document
We all take knocks in the process
broken backs, drownings, near-drownings, hypothermia, dislocations, fractures, frostbite, head wounds, stitches, concussions, broke my arm
and that’s just the last couple of years
still look forward to getting amongst it each winter though
Cold creeping into your core, driving you mad
day after day
mumbling to yourself while you hold position and wait for the next set to come
The dark side of the lens
An artform that to itself and us
silent workhorses of the surfing wake
There’s no sugary cliché
Most folk don’t even know who we are
what we do or how we do it
let alone what they pay us for it
I never want to take this for granted
so I try to keep motivation simple, real, and positive
If I only scrape a living
at least it’s a living where I’m scraping
If there’s no future in it
this is a present worth remembering
For fires of happiness and waves of gratitude
For everything that brought us to that point on earth at that moment in time
to do something worth remembering with a photograph
or a scar
I feel genuinely lucky to hand on heart say I love doing what I did
And I may never be a rich man
for live long enough
then sadly I have a tale or two for the nephews
And I dig the thought of that